ADHITHYAKRISHNA SRINIVASAN

adhithya.developer@gmail.com

Website | I

Linked-in

I am a software engineer with 3.5 years of work experience in e-commerce domain. I have worked as a frontend developer on technologies such as jQuery, handlebars, Html5 and CSS. I was promoted as a backend developer for developing microservices applications using Spring.

EXPERIENCE

Backend developer, Skava Systems - (DEC 2017 - JUN 2019)

- Developed Restful services for e-commerce website using Spring framework to handle user authentication, validation and storage of user information in MySQL database.
- Developed MapReduce project using Apache Hadoop to fetch profile data of users from MySQL database and store them to the Apache Solr server.
- Generated site usage report from Amazon Cloud Watch logs using Apache Hadoop which was used to analyze and improve the site's efficiency and decrease page load latency.

Frontend developer, Skava Systems - (JUN 2016 - NOV 2017)

- Developed responsive websites using mobile first approach using HTML5, CSS3, handlebars and jQuery that supported multitude of devices ranging from mobile to instore kiosks.
- Developed customizable plug-ins from scratch using jQuery to replace the feature-bloated third-party plug-ins.
- Integrated Google analytics to the website to analyze the traffic flow and site usage metrics in real-time.

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer science, University at Buffalo – (AUG 2019 – JAN 2021)

Pursuing my first semester. **Courses taken** – Information retrieval, Introduction to machine learning, Algorithms for modern computing systems and Object-oriented design and analysis.

Bachelors in Computer Science, Kumaraguru college of Technology – (AUG 2012 – AUG 2016)

Courses taken – Visual programming, Database management, Data structures, Object oriented programming, Computer architecture, Java programming, Compiler design.

SKILLS

Java
 Apache Solr
 MySql

JavaScript, jQuery
 Apache Hadoop
 Express JS

Python • Mongo dB • CSS 3

Html 5
 Maven

PROJECTS

Academic projects – <u>Twitter rhetoric analysis</u> - <u>Evaluation of information retrieval models</u>

Non-Academic projects – Sprite image mapper - Telegram to Gdrive